Agnès Garoux GitHub: nes11

- Self-taught full-stack JavaScript developer (as well as a trained language teacher)
- Dedicated to delivering value through elegant, clean code and Agile methodologies
- 2 years experience as a React/Node developer (1 year professionally)

I have now been a JavaScript developer for **2 years**, after leaving the teaching world behind (and I have not looked back!). A successful first role as a professional programmer had me working on a complex codebase with talented and experienced colleagues. I am now looking to take the next step in my career, with a company that values the **technical and soft skills** I bring to the table and will nurture my career as a developer.

I have strong interpersonal skills acquired through a long career as a teacher and a degree in communications. I am involved in the JavaScript community (e.g. London Node User Group), and I benefit from the mentorship of senior developers.

I have experience **building and maintaining front-end** (React.js) **and back-end** (Node.js) JavaScript codebases; I have worked with **containerised environments** (Docker) and a **variety of databases** (mostly PostgreSQL and MonogoDB). I am passionate about simple clean code, functional programming, CI/CD, and **Agile** (having briefly trained as an Agile Coach).

Personal projects accessible on https://github.com/nes11

Technical stack

JavaScript ES6 (React.js, Node.js, NPM,

Express.is)

React 16+ (Hooks, Context, Effects)

Databases (MongoDB, PostgreSQL/pgAdmin)

AWS's SNS, SQS, SES, dynamoDB

OS (Ubuntu: 1+ years, iOS)

TDD (Mocha, Chai, Jest)

Git/GitHub/Gitlab

Functional programming

VSCode, Atom

Docker Postman

Agile methodologies, especially SCRUM

Twillio's API/webhooks

Experience

May 2019 - present: full-stack JavaScript developer - VoxSmart

Voxsmart offers brokers and traders a unified comms surveillance platform, for regulatory compliance. We manage a microservices platform hosted on AWS ECS, with services written in JavaScript, Java & Python. As part of the 3-person JavaScript team, I am responsible for maintaining the integrity and accessibility of our data, and developing features for the main voice-recording server (integrating with Twilio). My current focus is on developing a backend server to support mobile IM capture. We follow design principles enforced by our team lead: clean code and refactoring, building things incrementally, and continuous integration.

January 2011 - July 2018: in Education: teacher, tutor, governess

I am a UK-trained teacher of Modern Foreign Language and I have applied my skills and knowledge in many different settings (private and state schools, as well as private households) with students within a wide age-range (primary and secondary, and adults).

January 2013 - February 2014: executive receptionist - Engie, La Défense (Paris) France I coordinated hospitality for the executive floors at Engie, with a focus on high-profile international visitors and the board of directors. I managed junior staff (PAs and other executive assistants) and the work of contractors, effectively a gatekeeper to the company's executives.

Education

Post Graduate Certificate in Education (September 2009-June 2010)

Cardiff Metropolitan University (formerly UWIC) - Cardiff, Wales

Secondary/Modern Foreign Languages, French specialist. The course included two 4-month school placements. I was first awarded a 2 (Good), then a 1 (Outstanding) after formal classroom-based assessments. I focussed on child protection, behaviour management, effective lesson planning and assessment. I conducted empirical studies into formative assessment and motivation for learning languages.

BA in Communication Studies (September 2002-June 2006)

SATCOM Université Paris VIII – St Denis, France

Multidisciplinary (i.e. semiotics, sociology, economy) study of Information, Communication and Media, including theory, case studies and practical applications.

Additional information

Languages: French (native speaker), English (fluent), Spanish (beginner)

I have the right to work in the UK

frangipane tart and more!

I have written, directed and edited short films ranging from documentary to satire and comedy. I love cooking, especially baking. My specialties include chocolate lave cakes, banana bread, pear

I enjoy making/customizing my clothing and have recently started doing embroidery.

I am training to run a 10k, I am strong swimmer and play badminton and table tennis.

I have always been an avid reader (classics, sci-fi/postmodernist novels, essays, and biographies).